Tlingit songs and texts collected by Nora Marks Dauenhauer and Richard Dauenhauer
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 1. Tlingit and English recordings, ca. 1950-1997 Bulk: 1970-1990
  - George Davis, March 13, 2008, Tape 45.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR037)
    Speaker's English name: George Davis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kichnáalx; Lk'aanáaw. Speaker's Moiety: Ts'axweil (Crow) *Raven. Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Carcross, Yukon. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: George Davis interview.
  - George Davis, October 13, 1973, Tape 46.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR038)
    Speaker's English name: George Davis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kichnáalx; Lk'aanáaw. Speaker's Moiety: Raven. Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Carcross, Yukon. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Potlatch for (Hinshoolk) David Hammond by Austin Hammond.
  - George Davis, October 13, 1973, Tape 47.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR039)
    Speaker's English name: George Davis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kichnáalx; Lk'aanáaw. Speaker's Moiety: Ts'axweil (Crow) *Raven. Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Carcross, Yukon. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Potlatch for (Hinshoolk) David Hammond by Austin Hammond.
  - George Davis, October 13, 1973, Tape 48.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR040)
  - Charlie Joseph interview, October 25, 1980, Tape 49.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR041)
    Speaker's English name: Charlie Joseph. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kaal.átk'. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Gooch (Wolf). Speaker's Clan: Kaagwaantaan (Sitka). Father's Clan: L'uknax.ádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Interview.
  - Annie Dick, October 25, 1980, Tape 50.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR042)
    Speaker's English name: Annie Dick. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kaasan'k. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Cheech (Porpoise). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Kaat'eix Mary Pelayo 40 Day party.
  - Annie Dick, October 25, 1980, Tape 51.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR043)
  - Unidentified, October 25, 1980, Tape 52 (?).; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR044)
    Speaker's English name: multiple. Speaker's Tlingit Name: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Kaat'eix Mary Pelayo 40 Day party.
  - Unidentified, October 25, 1980, Tape 53.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR045)
  - Unidentified, October 25, 1980, Tape 54.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR046)
  - Memorial for Houston, Wright, Martin, Hinchman, October 10, 1976, Tape 55.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR047)
    Speaker's English name: multiple. Speaker's Tlingit Name: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska (Cedar House). Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Chookaneidí Memorial.
  - Memorial for Houston, Wright, Martin, Hinchman, October 10, 1976, Tape 56.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR048)
  - Memorial for Houston, Wright, Martin, Hinchman, October 10, 1976, Tape 57.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR049)
  - Memorial for Houston, Wright, Martin, Hinchman, October 10, 1976, Tape 58.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR050)
  - Memorial for Houston, Wright, Martin, Hinchman, October 10, 1976, Tape 59.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR051)
  - Memorial for Houston, Wright, Martin, Hinchman, October 10, 1976, Tape 60.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR052)
  - Naanaahít and Bear House Songs, undated, Tape 61.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR053)
    Speaker's English name: Jim Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kuháanx'; Goox Guwakaan. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska (Cedar House). Recorded by: Lil White. Description of contents: Chookaneidí songs from Naanaahít and Bear House, Hoonah.
  - Willie Marks, Raven Stories, October 24, 1972, Tape 74.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR054)
    Speaker's English name: Willie Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Keet Yaanaayí. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Kaax'achgóok; Raven & Gull; Raven and Water; Raven and Fire; Raven and Tide; Raven and Whale. These stories are transcribed for Raven Book.
  - Willie Marks, Random Stories, March 29, 1976, Tape 75.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR055)
    Speaker's English name: Willie Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Keet Yaanaayí. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Tl'anaxéedakw (Lady of Auke Lake), Xakúch' (man who killed the Giant Devil Fish aka Octopus).
  - Willie Marks, October 25, 1980, Tape 76.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR056)
    Speaker's English name: Willie Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Keet Yaanaayí. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Story of Guxk'w Sákw, Guxk'w Sákw and his song. Relatives of Eliza Marks, T'akdeintaan. Xakw Chookan Heen and T'ooch'/gold. Raven and the Sun, Moon, and Stars. Tl'anaxéedakw.
  - Willie Marks, October 3, 1976, Tape 77.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR057)
    Speaker's English name: Willie Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Keet Yaanaayí. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Side 1. Willie Marks at Mt. Edge Cumbe.; David Kadashan at Sitka. Continuation of Guxk'w Sákw. Side 2. David Kadashan of Guxk'w Sákw continued; Ida Kadashan, Yeik.
  - Willie and Emma Marks, February 14, 1973, Tape 78.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR058)
    Speaker's English name: Willie and Emma Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Keet Yaanaayí (Willie), Seigeigéi (Emma). Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle) (Willie), Yéil (Raven) (Emma). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear) (Willie), Gaat (Sockeye) (Emma). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah) (Willie), L'ukaax.ádi (Dry Bay) (Emma). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Willie and Emma talk about proverbs. Bear Husband. Xakúch'.
  - Willie Marks, October 5, 1974, Tape 79.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR059)
    Speaker's English name: Willie Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Keet Yaanaayí. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Haines, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Story of Yuwaan Gagéets. Ending of a potlatch song, from Hoonah, Alaska.
  - Amy Marvin, May 31, 1984, Tape 80.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR060)
    Speaker's English name: Amy Marvin. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kooteen. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Interview about Glacier Bay (Alaska).
  - Austin Hammond, 1989, Tape 81.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR061)
    Speaker's English name: Austin Hammond. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Daanawáak. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: Lukaax.ádi (Haines). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Portland, Oregon. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Raven and his Nose [This tape excerpt is copied from the Rasmussen Conference set].
  - Jim Fox, 1960, Tape 82.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR062)
    Speaker's English name: Jim Fox. Speaker's Tlingit Name: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Carol Beery Davis. Description of contents: Interview. [Nora copied Mrs Davis's original on 23 August 1972].
  - A.P. Johnson; Forest Dewitt, undated, Tape 83.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR063)
    Speaker's English name: A.P. Johnson; Forest Dewitt. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Ixt'ik' Eesh; Hinwantáax'. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven); Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Xíxch' (Frog); Téel' (Dog Salmon). Speaker's Clan: Kiks.ádi (Sitka); L'eineidí (Juneau). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan; unknown. Language: English/Tlingit; Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska; Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: A.P. Johnson speech about lifestyle, beliefs, culture, religion; Forest Dewitt speech.
  - A.P. Johnson; Peter Nielson, April 1970, Tape 84.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR064)
    Speaker's English name: A.P. Johnson. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Ixt'ik' Eesh. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Xíxch' (Frog). Speaker's Clan: Kiks.ádi (Sitka). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Rosita and Bob Worl. Description of contents: Rambling.
  - A.P. Johnson, November 29, 1972, Tape 85.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR065)
    Speaker's English name: A.P. Johnson. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Ixt'ik' Eesh. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Xíxch' (Frog). Speaker's Clan: Kiks.ádi (Sitka). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Origin of Mosquito and Giant Lady. *Recording is damaged.
  - A.P. Johnson, June 6, 1973, Tape 86.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR066)
    Speaker's English name: A.P. Johnson. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Ixt'ik' Eesh. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Xíxch' (Frog). Speaker's Clan: Kiks.ádi (Sitka). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Begins with modern times Tlingits. Then a story about Kooshda.
  - George Dalton, undated, Tape 87.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR067)
    Speaker's English name: George Dalton. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Stoowukáa;Kaadéik. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Gooch (Wolf). Speaker's Clan: Kaagwaantaan (Sitka). Father's Clan: T'akdeintaan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Ken Austin. Description of contents: Story.
  - Sitka dancers: Bert Dennis; Jessie Dalton, June 19, 1972, Tape 88.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR068)
    Speaker's English name: Bert Dennis; Jessie Dalton. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Aan kadaxtseen; Daax'wudaak; Naa Tláa. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven); Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Gaat (Sockeye); unknown. Speaker's Clan: Lukaax.ádi (Duncan Canal); T'akdeintaan. Father's Clan: unknown; Wooshkeetaan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Interview; Interview, Mt. Edgecumbe Hospital.
  - Jimmie George, June 1, 1988, Tape 89.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR069)
    Speaker's English name: Jimmie George. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Wóochx Kaduhaa. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Killer Whale. Speaker's Clan: Dakl'aweidí. Father's Clan: Deisheetaan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Interview.
  - Jimmie George, June 1, 1988, Tape 90.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR070)
  - George Jim, tape 1, undated, Tape 91.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR071)
    Speaker's English name: George Jim. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Keikóok'w. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Wooshkeetaan. Father's Clan: L'uknax.ádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Angoon, Alaska. Recorded by: Andrew Hope III. Description of contents: Interview.
  - George Jim, tape 2, undated, Tape 92.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR072)
  - George Jim, tape 3, undated, Tape 93.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR073)
  - George Jim, December 6, 1972, Tape 94.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR074)
  - George Jim, undated, Tape 95.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR075)
  - George Jim, June 2, 1988, Tape 96.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR076)
    Speaker's English name: George Jim. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Keikóok'w. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Wooshkeetaan. Father's Clan: L'uknax.ádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Angoon, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Interview.
  - George Jim, September 9, 1989, Tape 97.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR077)
  - Jenny Marks, August 18, 1972, Tape 98.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR078)
    Speaker's English name: Jenny Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kus.een. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: Lukaax.ádi (Duncan Canal);Talku (Devils Thumb Mtn). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: John Marks. Description of contents: Interview.
  - David Williams, undated, Tape 99.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR079)
    Speaker's English name: David Williams. Speaker's Tlingit Name: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Interview.
  - Mamie Williams, August 11, 1972, Tape 100.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR080)
    Speaker's English name: Mamie Williams. Speaker's Tlingit Name: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Interview.
  - David Kadashan, August 9, 1972, Tape 101.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR081)
    Speaker's English name: David Kadashan. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kaatyé. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: T'akdeintaan. Father's Clan: Shangukeidí. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Inaudible.
  - David Kadashan, August 10, 1972, Tape 102.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR082)
    Speaker's English name: David Kadashan. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kaatyé. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: T'akdeintaan. Father's Clan: Shangukeidí. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Inaudible; Listing traditional T'akdeintaan houses in Hoonah. He's talking about At.oow, and that you have to take care of it. He talks about the snail house, arctic turns. He sings the mountain dog hat song as well. He tells story "To Be a Slave" (Guxk'w Sákw).
  - David Kadashan, April 1, 1973, Tape 103.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR083)
    Speaker's English name: David Kadashan. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kaatyé. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: T'akdeintaan. Father's Clan: Shangukeidí. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Listing traditional Chookaneidí houses in Hoonah. He talks about the small pox epidemic. He also talks about when school's just began. He tells clan stories, and how they made boats.
  - David Kadashan, April 1, 1973, Tape 104.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR084)
    Speaker's English name: David Kadashan. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kaatyé. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: T'akdeintaan. Father's Clan: Shangukeidí. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Tells how Haidas had gotten to the Alaska mainland. And how the Tlingits learned how to build boats.
  - David Kadashan, April 24, 1973, Tape 105.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR085)
    Speaker's English name: David Kadashan. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kaatyé. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: T'akdeintaan. Father's Clan: Shangukeidí. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Songs - group unknown.
  - David Kadashan, John Marks, October 6, 1974, Tape 106.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR086)
    Speaker's English name: David Kadashan. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kaatyé. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: T'akdeintaan. Father's Clan: Shangukeidí. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Haines, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Discussing song Kaax'achgóok. Sings Interior Indian Songs.
  - Ida Kadashan, July 12, 1972, Tape 107.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR087)
    Speaker's English name: Ida Kadashan. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kaashtunaa. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Thunderbird. Speaker's Clan: Shangukeidí. Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: unknown. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Interview with Ida Kadashan.
  - Harry Bremner, tape 1, December 31, 1964, Tape 108.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR088)
    Speaker's English name: Harry Bremner. Speaker's Tlingit Name: unknown. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Humpy Salmon. Speaker's Clan: K'waashk'i Kwaan. Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Yakutat, Alaska. Recorded by: SNEP. Description of contents: History of Yakutat tape 1 side 1 recorded 12-31-64. Handwriting on the box and cassetter look like Andy Hope's. The original was probably made by Frederica de Laguna. There are probably copies of the originals in the SHI archives.
  - Harry Bremner, tape 2, December 31, 1964, Tape 109.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR089)
    Speaker's English name: Harry Bremner. Speaker's Tlingit Name: unknown. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Humpy Salmon. Speaker's Clan: K'waashk'i Kwaan. Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Yakutat, Alaska. Recorded by: SNEP. Description of contents: History of Yakutat Tape 2. Recorded 12-31-64. Handwriting on the box looks like Andy Hope's. The original was probably made by Frederica de Lagauna. There are probably copies or originals in the SHI archives.
  - Frank Italio, copy 1, September 13, 1952, Tape 110.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR090)
    Speaker's English name: Frank Italio. Speaker's Tlingit Name: unknown. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Thunderbird. Speaker's Clan: Shangukeidí. Father's Clan: L'uknax.adi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Yakutat, Alaska. Recorded by: Fredercia de Laguna. Description of contents: Frank is talking about raven and the whale. He is talking about box of daylight. Bird that dances on the edge of the river. *added by Kaawus.aa* Lk'ayaak' man that did 'crazy' things, he was unorthodox and hyperactive.
  - Frank Italio, copy 2, September 13, 1952, Tape 110.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR091)
  - Frank Italio, 1, July 30, 1952, Tape 111.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR092)
    Speaker's English name: Frank Italio. Speaker's Tlingit Name: unknown. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Thunderbird. Speaker's Clan: Shangukeidí. Father's Clan: L'uknax.adi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Yakutat, Alaska. Recorded by: Fredercia de Laguna. Description of contents: This is a copy of the original recording by Frederica de Laguna, Yakutat, July 30, 1952. Card insert notes Nora Dauenhauer audit time of November 29, 1999. Contents: 1 Maker of Thunderbird Screen, K'washnáa; 2, Sit' aayí, thunderbird song in athabaskan; 3 Interpretation, the handling of at.óow; 4 Thunderbird screen and song and interpretation of use; 5, interruption; 6, explanation by de Laguna.
  - Frank Italio, 2, July 30, 1952, Tape 111.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR093)
  - Frank Italio, copy 2, July 30, 1952, Tape 111.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR094)
  - Frank Italio, raven, 1952, Tape 112.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR095)
    Speaker's English name: Frank Italio. Speaker's Tlingit Name: unknown. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Thunderbird. Speaker's Clan: Shangukeidí. Father's Clan: L'uknax.adi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Yakutat, Alaska. Recorded by: Fredercia de Laguna. Description of contents: Frank Italio, Raven.
  - Robert Zuboff, July 26, 1972, Tape 114.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR096)
    Speaker's English name: Robert Zuboff. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Shaadaax'. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Kak'weidí; Deisheetaan. Father's Clan: Dakl'weidí yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: unknown. Description of contents: Kaax'achgóok. Box and tape have old label #7.
  - Robert Zuboff, July 26, 1972, Tape 115.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR097)
    Speaker's English name: Robert Zuboff. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Shaadaax'. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Kak'weidí; Deisheetaan. Father's Clan: Dakl'weidí yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Box and tape have old label #3.
  - Robert Zuboff, November 7, 1972, Tape 116.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR098)